<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>New to legato and mangoh, help needed</title>
    <link>https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505</link>
    <description>Hello everyone, 

I&#39;m an electrical engineer and recently my job has turned a lot more software-based than the hardware and embedded C I&#39;m used to. I purchased a mangoh red board to determine viability for one of our projects. I&#39;ve followed the setup instructions for linux exactly. After overcoming quite a few issues and then being stumped on what seems like the last 5 yards, I finally vaporized that VM and installed the gui developer studio. I&#39;m still having issues, but at least I can compile the &quot;Hello World&quot; program. Although for the life of me, I can&#39;t seem to compile any of the other programs. 

I just want to change the output of one GPIO pin so I can see something on my DSO. I&#39;m scoping the IoT breakout connector, and the RPi header but none of the gpio programs seem to work, even the github programs crash frequently/do not compile.

Is this normal? Am I missing something?

I&#39;ve tried making everything from the command line again, but still can&#39;t make legato for the wp77xx, or mangoh for the red_wp77xx. Can someone give me some direction here? I&#39;ve included a txt of the command line output when trying to make wp77xx in the legato directory. [failed make output 1.txt|attachment](upload://4g6Cebc106gNkquJMzROArXAn23.txt) (106.0 KB)

Thanks, 
Connor</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 02:57:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>mangOH Red</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>New to legato and mangoh, help needed</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[jyijyi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Here is an example to change output state of GPIO13:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="7" data-topic="4522">
  <div class="title">
    <div class="quote-controls"></div>
    <img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://avatars.discourse-cdn.com/v4/letter/s/76d3ee/40.png" class="avatar">
    <a href="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/is-there-a-sample-app-using-gpio-pin/4522/7">Is there a sample app using gpio pin?</a> <a class="badge-wrapper  bullet" href="https://forum.mangoh.io/c/mangoh-yellow/15"><span class="badge-category-bg" style="background-color: #F1C900;"></span><span style="" data-drop-close="true" class="badge-category clear-badge">mangOH Yellow</span></a>
  </div>
  <blockquote>
    I used the sysfs command, but I don’t know what api can be used to produce the desired output on the digital pin through which function call can be used.
  </blockquote>
</aside>

<p>BTW, you should use developer studio as it has been end of life.<br>
VSCode + LEAF should be used:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric" data-onebox-src="https://docs.legato.io/latest/tools_vsCode.html">
  <header class="source">
      

      <a href="https://docs.legato.io/latest/tools_vsCode.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">docs.legato.io</a>
  </header>

  <article class="onebox-body">
    

<h3><a href="https://docs.legato.io/latest/tools_vsCode.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Legato Plugin for VSCode  - Legato Docs</a></h3>

  <p>legato™ is an open source Linux-based embedded platform designed to simplify connected IoT application development</p>


  </article>

  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>

  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 01:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.mangoh.io-post-1505-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505.rss">New to legato and mangoh, help needed</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>New to legato and mangoh, help needed</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[CT1]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Furthermore, if anyone can recommend any good books on learning embedded linux, I’d greatly appreciate it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 23:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.mangoh.io-post-1505-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505.rss">New to legato and mangoh, help needed</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>New to legato and mangoh, help needed</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[CT1]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello everyone,</p>
<p>I’m an electrical engineer and recently my job has turned a lot more software-based than the hardware and embedded C I’m used to. I purchased a mangoh red board to determine viability for one of our projects. I’ve followed the setup instructions for linux exactly. After overcoming quite a few issues and then being stumped on what seems like the last 5 yards, I finally vaporized that VM and installed the gui developer studio. I’m still having issues, but at least I can compile the “Hello World” program. Although for the life of me, I can’t seem to compile any of the other programs.</p>
<p>I just want to change the output of one GPIO pin so I can see something on my DSO. I’m scoping the IoT breakout connector, and the RPi header but none of the gpio programs seem to work, even the github programs crash frequently/do not compile.</p>
<p>Is this normal? Am I missing something?</p>
<p>I’ve tried making everything from the command line again, but still can’t make legato for the wp77xx, or mangoh for the red_wp77xx. Can someone give me some direction here? I’ve included a txt of the command line output when trying to make wp77xx in the legato directory. <a class="attachment" href="https://forum.mangoh.io/uploads/short-url/4g6Cebc106gNkquJMzROArXAn23.txt">failed make output 1.txt</a> (106.0 KB)</p>
<p>Thanks,<br>
Connor</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 22:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.mangoh.io-post-1505-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.mangoh.io/t/new-to-legato-and-mangoh-help-needed/1505.rss">New to legato and mangoh, help needed</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
